Open Seams
I'm L.
L です
This guy is L?
この男が…
That's not quite the image I had of him...
なんかイメージが…
The name's Yagami, I'm with the police force.
警察庁の夜神です
I'm Matsuda.
あ、松田です
I'm Aizawa.
相沢です
I'm Mogi.
模木です
I'm Ukita.
宇生田です
Sorry we're late.
遅くなってすまない、
Currently, the five of us..
この五人が現在の…
Bang!
バン
な…
What the hell are you playing at?
何の真似だ！
If I was Kira, you'd be dead by now, Yagami Souichirou-san.
もし私がキラだったら死んでますよ、夜神総一郎さん
In order to kill, Kira needs a face and a name.
キラが殺人に必要なのは顔と名前…
All of you should know this by now.
そんな事はもう分っている筈でしょ
Try not to carelessly reveal your names.
不用意に名前渡さないで下さい
Let's try to value our lives.
命は大切にしましょう
I've heard that the face is essential, but I've heard nothing about Kira needing to know the victim's name as well...
顔は聞いてましたけど…
名前が必要なんて話、出てましたっけ…
All the high profile criminals whose real names are unknown or were reported wrongly have escaped Kira's wrath.
名前が分らない…
或いは名前を間違って報道されていた大物犯罪者の全てが…
キラから免れている
It's an issue that's also been discussed at Investigative Headquarters.
捜査本部でも言われていた事だ
Standing around there chatting is all very well, but please come this way.
立ち話もなんですから…こちらへどうぞ
Umm.. okay...
ああ…はい
I must ask you to switch off all cell phones, laptops and other transmission devices and leave them on the table there.
携帯やノートパソコン
その他の通信機器は電源を切って、
そちらのテーブルにお願いします
L! Are you trying to suggest that we'd use our cell phones to let people listen in on this?!
L ！我々は携帯を通話状態にして、外に流すとでも…
Let's just forget about that now and do as he asks.
いいから、言われた通りに…
We've known from the start the he's the cautious type, but it's hard to tell if he really trusts us or not.
用心深いのは最初からだけど…
信用されてるんだかされてないんだか…
No... it's just that I can't stand people's phones going off while I'm trying to talk.
いいえ、自分が話している時に、
人の携帯が鳴るのは許せないだけです
I'd better tell you this now.. I don't want anyone making notes for anyone of what's being discussed here.
最初にいっときますが…
ここを本部で私が話す事は、
メモなどは一切取らずに、頭の中に入れてください
Please, sit down.
どうぞ
適当に掛けてください
Err... L?
あの… L
私を呼ぶ時は今後 L ではなく…竜崎でお願いします
Please, from now on, call me "Ryuuzaki" instead of "L", just to be on the safe side.
用心の為に
In that case.. uh, Ryuuzaki...
あ…じゃあ竜崎、
If you already know that Kira needs both a name and face, why don't we just withhold criminal information from the media? Surely that will reduce the number of victims?
顔と名前が必要と分ってるなら
犯罪者の報道を規制すれば、犠牲者を減らせるのでは？
If we did that, members of the public would end up being killed.
そんなことしたら一般人が殺されます
Members of the public?
一般人が？
Why?
何故？
Kira is immature, and is a bad loser.
キラは幼稚で負けず嫌いだ
Immature?
幼稚で…
Bad loser?
負けず嫌い？
Yes.
そう、私も幼稚で負けず嫌い、
I know, because I'm also immature and hate to lose.
だから分る
Ryuuzaki, could you explain that better for us?
竜崎…、もう少し分りやすく話してくれないか…
When I used that TV broadcast to challenge Kira, despite the fact that Kira had only killed criminals up until then, they killed the fake version of me without any hesitation.
私がテレビを使ってキラに宣戦布告した時…
それまで犯罪者しか殺していなかったと思われるキラは…
When I used that TV broadcast to challenge Kira, despite the fact that Kira had only killed criminals up until then, they killed the fake version of me without any hesitation.
躊躇う事なく私の替え玉を殺し…
そして、「日本の関東に潜伏している」と言うと、
And when I disclosed the fact that I knew they were from the Kanto region of Japan, they immediately began to kill mainly Japanese criminals as if to say, "So what?".
「だからどうした」と言わんばかりに
日本の犯罪者を中心に殺し始めた
Instead of backing down from my provocations, they have been aggressively returning them.
こちらの挑発には怯む事なく、強気に挑発し返してくる…
If you try to withhold information from someone who acts like this, what do you think will happen?
こんな行動するものに
報道規制で悪人を隠したりしたら…どうなると思います？
Well, that's..
それは…
If there are no proper criminals to kill, they'll go after the petty ones, if there there aren't any of them, they'll be targeting the innocent.
「悪人を出さなければ罪の軽い者…罪の無い者でも殺す」
Everyone on this planet is being held hostage.
「全世界の人間が人質だ」
"I'm not the one who's in the wrong here. Those who try to hide the criminals from me are the ones who are in the wrong."
「悪いのは私じゃない」
「私に逆らい悪人を隠す…お前らが悪だ｣
That is how Kira thinks.
これがキラの思考回路です
If anything, we should really be thinking of ways of using the media to our own advantage.
どうせなら…マスコミを利用する事を考えましょうよ
For example?
例えは…？
Well, how about this?
こういうのはどうでしょう…
"The Americans are angered by the murders of their FBI agents. The entire world turns against Kira. Approximately 1,500 investigators from powerful nations enter Japan."
FBI 殺しにアメリカ激怒…
キラに全世界が憤り、
先進各国から日本に千五百人の捜査員導入…
Kira will have a lot more than the FBI to deal with this time.
キラはこの間の FBI どころではなくなる…
They'll begin to perceive absolutely everyone to be their enemy.
外にいる者が全て敵に見え、
Feeling trapped, Kira will give us some kind of reaction.
精神的に追い詰められたキラは何らかの反応を起す…
I-Interesting...
お…面白い
They'll think that there are 1,500 people after them, even though in reality there's only seven!
実際は七員しか動いてないのに、千五百人か…
And since the investigators don't exist, they can't kill them!
しかも FBI と違って、実在してないんだから殺せない
This could really work!
いけますよ
In that case, let me tell you some of my thoughts regarding this case.
ではキラ事件に関する私の考えを話しましょう
Kira is a loner.
キラは単独犯、
Somehow, they were accessing information from the previous headquarters.
前の捜査本部の情報を得ていた
その…単独犯っていうのはどういう理由で…
How can you tell that they're a loner?
Hang on a minute Aizawa. Let's listen to all of Ryuuzaki's reasonings first.
待って相沢、
まず竜崎の推理を全部聞こう
In order to kill, they require both a name and a face.
殺しに必要なのは顔と名前…
They can also manipulate the time of death, and to some extent, the victim's movements prior to death.
そして死の時間、死の前の行動をある程度操れる
Having absorbed what I just said, please listen closely to the following.
以上の事を頭によく入れた上で…
これから話すことを聞いて下さい
On the 14th December, twelve FBI agents entered Japan.
十二月十四日…
FBI 捜査官十二人が日本に入っています
On the 14th December, twelve FBI agents entered Japan.
On the 19th December, Kira is evidently using prisoners as test subjects in order to study how they could manipulate the victim's movements before death.
十二月十九日…
キラは明らかに、
刑務所の犯罪者で死の前の行動を操るテストをしています
To put it simply, during these five days, Kira became aware of the FBI's presence in Japan, and felt threatened by them.
つまり…
このたった五日の間に…
To put it simply, during these five days, Kira became aware of the FBI's presence in Japan, and felt threatened by them.
キラは FBI の存在に気付き脅威に感じた
From this we can deduce that to kill the FBI agents whose names and faces they didn't know,
そこで顔も名前も分らない、 FBI 全員を消す為に、
Kira found it necessary to experiment to see how far they could manipulate someone's death.
死をどこまで操れるか
テストする必要があったと考えられます
And then on the 27th December...
そして十二月二十七日…
Was able to put files containing the names and faces of everyone involved into the hands of every agent on the team, and succeeded in killing them all.
FBI 捜査官全員に…
彼らの顔と名前の入ったファイルを持たせて、
殺すことに成功…
Was able to put files containing the names and faces of everyone involved into the hands of every agent on the team, and succeeded in killing them all.
As a result, it's almost impossible to tell whose files I looked at in order to kill the agents.
これでキラが誰のファイルを見たのか
推測することはほぼ不可能…
But.. the fact that I encountered Ray Penber must never be discovered by anyone.
…しかし
あのレイ．ペンバーと接触した事は…
絶対に知られてはならない
Huh? Not using the Death Note today?
あれ？今日はデスノートじゃないんだな…
This is for those "exams"?
例の受験ってヤツか？
It's too late to still be trying to study for them.
そんな勉強…今頃してるようじゃなめなよ
Then what?
うお、じゃ何？
The period from the 19th to the 27th December... is when I've been most active.
十二月十九日から二十七日…
僕が一番動いたのはここだ
During this time, as far as we can tell, 23 people have died of a heart attack.
この間に…
今分っているだけで、23人が心臓麻痺で亡くなっています
These 23 people were all either suspected criminals or previous offenders, either guilty of lesser crimes or only suspected of wrongdoing.
この23人は…指名手配犯や前科者
罪の疑いが掛かっているだけの者で、
This is clearly different from Kira's previous targets.
明らかに今までのキラのターゲットとは異なっている…
That's true.
確かに…
This suggests that for Kira to kill the FBI agents, it was necessary to manipulate these people.
つまりキラは、 FBI を消すのに、
罪の軽い者でも操る必要があった…
They killed 23 people to make it harder for us to identify who was actually killed as part of the plan.
23人と多いのは、誰を利用したか絞り込めなくする為…
In reality, it's likely that Kira only used a few of them.
実際に利用したのは数人でしょう
The fact that there were eight days between the tests being performed, and Kira acting,
テストから実行まで八日空いているのも、
indicates that they allowed the agents to investigate as many people as possible to draw suspicion away from themselves.
FBI により多くの物を調べさせ、自分を隠す為です
Consequently, Kira must be someone that was under investigation by the FBI between the 14th and the 19th.
だからキラは、この十四日から…
十九日に FBI が調べていた者の中にいたと考えて…
まず間違えありません
I've compiled data from the FBI and other necessary information together, although, I'm afraid that I won't let you take them away from here--
これに FBI からの情報…
そのほか必要なデータがまとめてあります
外部への持ち出しは一切禁止しますが…
Amazing!
凄い！
This is amazing!
凄いですよ！
If we know this much, we should be able to make progress, even if it's just the seven of us!
ここまで分っていれば、我々だけでも十分できる
We've got to check up on the past movements of the FBI and the heart attack victims.
FBI と…心臓麻痺者の足取りを追う、
二班に分れよう
We should split into two groups.
There aren't a lot of people who had access to police information and were investigated during that period.
本部の情報を得られた者で、
FBI が最初の五日で調べられた人間なんて…
かなり少ないですね
So, any questions?
で、何か質問は？
Then, Ryuuzaki, let me ask you one thing. You said that like Kira, you hate to lose.
では竜崎…
一つだけ聞かせてくれ
Then, Ryuuzaki, let me ask you one thing. You said that like Kira, you hate to lose.
あなたはさっき自分を負けず嫌いだと言っていたが…
Doesn't the fact that you've had to show us your face mean that you've lost to Kira?
我々に顔を見せるのはあなたにとって、
キラに負けた事になっていないか？
That's right.
そうです
That I've had to show my face and allowed twelve FBI agents to die, are my losses.
顔を出してしまった事も、
FBI 十二人を犠牲にしてしまった事も負けです
But I will win in the end.
しかし最後は勝ちます
This is the first time that I've had to lay down my life in a contest.
私も命を掛けた勝負は初めてです
As people willing to place our lives on the line, let's show Kira... that justice will always prevail.
ここに集まった命がけの人間で…見せてやりましょうよ
正義は必ず勝つという事を…
Y-Yes, that's right!
そ、そうとも…
Justice will triumph!
正義は勝ちますよ！
Let's try our best!
頑張りましょう
Alright! Let's do this, Ryuuzaki!
よし、やりますよ竜崎
When I first saw him, I wondered whether he was the real thing, but now I'm sure that he's the real L.
正直…最初に見た時は本物か疑ったが…
間違いない、この男が L …
First, I'd like to determine that Kira is not amongst us by having a one-on-one discussion with each of you.
ではまず…
この中にキラがいないことを確認する為に、
一人ずつお話をさせて戴きたいんですが…
He still doesn't trust us...
信用してなかったのか…
It's a reasonable request.
いや、もっともの話だ…
If Kira really is getting information from the police, there's a high possibility that he could be here.
キラが始めから本部内にいて情報を得ていたのなら…
ここに残っている可能性は高い
Of course! If they stayed on the case, they'd get to see Ryuuzaki's face, wouldn't they...
そうか…残れば、竜崎の顔見られたわけですしね
This is what it means to put your life on the line...
これだって命がけか…
So far so good...
ここまではいい…
Just one more... if only there was one more conclusive fact..
あと一つ…あと一つ何か決定的なものがあれば…
If there was a hole in my plan... if a single fact gets out... it could cost me my life.
何か一つでも穴があったら…
何か一つ、新事実が出てきたら…
If there was a hole in my plan... if a single fact gets out... it could cost me my life.
命取りになる
Just one thing...
何か一つ…
You finished studying then?
お勉強は終わったのか…
まぁね
I guess..
It's okay, there were no holes in my plan.
大丈夫だ、穴はない…
The riskiest incident was the bus hi-jacking.
一番リスクが大きかったのは、バスジャックの一件だが…
But there's no way that they'll be able to connect that to Kira, since L and the police believe that Kira can only kill via heart attacks.
あれをキラと結び付ける事はできない…
警察も L も…
But there's no way that they'll be able to connect that to Kira, since L and the police believe that Kira can only kill via heart attacks.
キラが心臓麻痺以外で人を殺せる事を知らないのだから…
On the other hand, if that fact was found out, it would become a massive hole in my plans...
裏を返せば…
その事実を知られたら、かなり大きな穴に…
What? Now?
え～、今から～？
お父さん着替えも無しに徹夜してるのよ、届けてあげなきゃ…
Dad's working all night without a change of clothes, so we should take some over.
But I promised to go to the New Year's festival with my friend!
友だちと初詣の約束してるの
I'll go.
僕が行くよ
It'll be nice to have a change of scene.
…気分転換に
Lucky! Thank you, onii-chan!
ラッキー～、お兄ちゃんサンキュ
I guess this means that you get to go spy on Police Headquarters.
警察庁にスパイにいけるってわけだ…
Even if I go, I'll only get as far as the reception desk.
行けても受付前だけどね…
You're taking a page with you?
お、1ページ持っていくのか
You're going to kill someone in the open?
外で殺し？
I've made a habit of doing this every time I go out... just in case...
最近外に出る時は、
いつもこうしてるよ、念のためにね
That day... I remember Ray saying he was going to Shinjuku.
あの日…レイは確かに「新宿に行く」と言っていた
On that same day, four relatively innocent people died of heart attacks around Shinjuku station...
その日に新宿駅周辺で、
四人もの心臓麻痺…
...and...
そして、バスジャック…
...that bus hi-jack!
偶然なんかじゃない…
It can't be just a coincidence.
Kira...
キラは…
...can kill people by means other than just a heart attack.
心臓麻痺以外でも人を殺せる…
お掛けになった電話は、現在電波が届かないところにあった
The number you have dialled is unavailable..
珍しいの、父さんは…
That's not like dad...
I wonder if there's an important meeting going on or something?
重要な会議でもしてるのか…
I'm begging you, please let me speak to the Investigative Headquarters in person.
お願いします
どうしても、捜査本部の方に直接お話したいんです
Like we keep saying, there's no one there at the moment.
だから…何度も言っているように、
キラ事件の捜査本部は、今は誰もいないんです
No one at headquarters?
本部に誰もいない？
His cell phone redirects to the answering machine too. What's going on?
携帯は留守電…
どうなってるんだ？
なんとか連絡つきませんか？
Is there a way in which I can contact them?
This is extremely important; it's about the Kira investigation.
キラ事件に関する重要なことなんです
The Kira investigation!
キラ事件の?!
Well, I'll try ringing headquarters again...
じゃあ､もう一度本部に電話してみますから…
I'm Chief Yagami Souichirou's son, Light.
刑事局夜神総一郎の息子、月です
I've brought him a change of clothes, but seeing that he doesn't seem to be around, could you look after them for me?
父の着替えなんですが…
いないようですし預かってもらえますか
Ah, Light-kun, good to see you again.
ああ、月君久し振り
あっ、すみません、えっと…
Err.. I'm sorry I...
I was also here that time your advice helped us in solving that insurance money killing case, last year.
ほら、去年月君の助言で解決した、保険金殺人事件
あの時も僕、ここで受付して…
Ah, is that it? Sorry about that.
そうでしたか…失礼しました
ここに名前を書けばいいんですよね？
Should I write my name here?
やっぱりキラ事件も…月君なりに推理しているわけ？
Have you been trying to rationalize the Kira investigation too, Light-kun?
Yes. If all goes well, I'll solve it before L does.
ええ、うまく行けば L を出し抜けるかも
Solve it before L?
L を出し抜く…
I'm sorry, but it really does seem like there's nobody at headquarters.
やっぱり本部には誰もいませんね…
Please, try to believe me.
少しは信用してくださいよ、ちゃんと私から伝えますので…
I'll pass on your message.
That's no good. I've got to speak to them directly!
ダメなんです、直接でなければ…
Excuse me. My father's the Chief Investigator for the Kira investigation.
あの…僕の父は、キラ事件の本部長ですから
If you like, I could try to get a hold of him.
もしよければ、取り次ぎましょうか？
I won't be able to do that immediately though, his cell phone is switched off.
携帯切ってるみたいなので、今すぐとはいきませんが…
FBI の人が殺されて
After the deaths of the FBI agents, a lot of people have been resigning within headquarters because they fear Kira.
ここの本部でも、キラを恐れる辞める者が続出し…
ごたごたしてるんだと思います
I can imagine it being a very hectic time for them.
Light-kun, you shouldn't tell members of the public things like that.
月君、そういうことは一般の人には…
People are already gossiping about this.
もう、世間では噂になってることですよ
Besides, this person can be trusted.
それにこの人は信用できる、目を見れば分ります
I can see it in her eyes. She's an intelligent and prudent person.
賢明で慎重な人です
Because of what happened to the FBI, you've realized that there's a problem within the police force, and that's why you wish to speak directly to headquarters.
FBI の事件で、日本の警察内部にも問題があることが分った
だから本部に直接話したい、
そこまで考えてるんだ…そうですよね
Right?
I figure that my father will eventually pick up his voice-mail and call me back.
そのうち留守電を聞いて、父から電話が入ると思います
If you don't mind waiting, you can speak to him directly then.
その時でよければ、直接お話し下さい
いいん…ですか？
Are you sure that's okay?
Yes. Of course, I can't give you my father's number, but you're welcome to use my cell phone to talk to him.
はい、父の携帯番号を教えるわけにはいきませんが…
僕の携帯を通して話す分には…
Anyway, it won't mean much until you decide to trust me or my father.
もっとも、父も僕も信用して頂けないと無理ですけどね
What's with the sudden cheerful demeanor?
何その明るいキャラ…
お願いします
Thank you.
うまく釣れたな、ライト
Looks like you've fooled her, Light!
You've certainly got a lot of courage to try and get involved with the Kira investigation.
それにしても、あなたは勇気がありますね
キラ事件に関わろうとするなんて…
Not really.
いえ…
あなたの考えでは、キラは…
According to your thinking, Kira... um, could I at least ask you for your name?
あの…一応お名前を聞かせてもらえますか？僕は夜神月
I'm Yagami Light.
It's written as "god of the night" (夜神), and then the character for "moon" (月), except you read it as "light".
夜の神に、月と書いて、
「ライト」と読ませるんです…変ってるでしょ？
Unusual, huh?
I'm Maki Shoko.
間木照子です
間、樹木の木に、照らすに子供の子です
Spelt with the characters "interval" (間) and "tree" (木), and then "illuminate" (照) and "child" (子).
間木さん…ですね
So, it's Maki-san, right?
ちから
間木さん、僕が考えてるキラの能力というのは…
Maki-san, according to my theory, Kira can manipulate people before killing them.
キラが人を殺す前に、その行動を操れるって事です
Me too!
私も…
I've been thinking the exact same thing!
私も同じ事を考えていたんです
"Kira can manipulate people before killing them", but that's not all. If I'm right... Kira can kill people using methods other than heart attacks.
キラは死の前の行動を操れる、それだけじゃない
私の考えが正しければ…
"Kira can manipulate people before killing them", but that's not all. If I'm right... Kira can kill people using methods other than heart attacks.
キラは…心臓麻痺以外でも、人を殺せる
Who is this woman?!
何なんだ、この女…
I don't think anyone else has realized yet, but if we assume this to be true... I think Kira knows they'll be caught.
多分まだ誰も気付いてない…
でも、この事を前提にすれば、キラは捕まるっと思ってます…
I don't think anyone else has realized yet, but if we assume this to be true... I think Kira knows they'll be caught.
I haven't thought that far ahead yet, but if that's true, the murders that Kira really wants to hide... will be by methods other than heart attacks?
そこまでは僕も考えたことはなかった…
でもそうだとすれば、
キラが本当に隠したい殺人は、心臓麻痺以外で行う
Yes, and I think someone I know met Kira.
はい、私の知り合いが、多分キラに会ってます
Kira?!
キラに…！
I'm sorry.. it's true that if you told the police that, they'd never believe you.
あ、失礼、キラに会ってるなんて…
確かに警察に言っても、信じてもらえないですよね
I'm sorry.. it's true that if you told the police that, they'd never believe you.
Yes, that's why I wanted to speak to someone in the investigation directly, and explain that I've got a reasonable case.
はい…だからこそ、捜査本部の方に
筋道を立てて、詳しく説明したいんです
Yes, that's why I wanted to speak to someone in the investigation directly, and explain that I've got a reasonable case.
But, in that case, wouldn't it be better if the person who met Kira talked to the police?
しかし、それなら会った本人が話した方が…いいのでは？
…その人はもうこの世にいません
That person is no longer with us...
He was one of the FBI agents who came to Japan.
日本に入った FBI 捜査官の一人でしたから…
An FBI investigator... who met Kira?!
キラに会った… FBI 捜査官…
Surely not?!
まさか…
He was also my fiancé.
彼は私のフィアンセでもあったんです
He said that he was randomly caught up in a bus hi-jacking, but if my theory is correct, he met Kira on that bus.
偶然バスジャックに巻き込まれたと言っていましたが…
キラに会ったのは、おそらくそのバスの中…
Ray... Penber!
レイ．ペンバー…
どうしました？
What's wrong?
It's nothing.. I had no idea that you'd lost your fiancé.
あっいえ、フィアンセを亡くされていたなんて…
So, why do you think he met Kira on that bus?
で、何故バスの中でキラに会ったとは？
After being caught up in that bus hi-jacking, he died eight days later along with eleven other FBI agents.
彼はバスジャックに遭遇した八日後…
他の FBI 捜査官と共に死にました…
Two days earlier, the culprit of the bus hi-jacking committed a bank robbery, and in the end he died in an accident.
バスジャック犯は、
その二日前に銀行を襲った犯人でした
Two days earlier, the culprit of the bus hi-jacking committed a bank robbery, and in the end he died in an accident.
そして最後は…事故死
It's not something that has been seen before.
余り例のない事です
I can only imagine that the bus hi-jack was set up, so that Kira could obtain information on the FBI agents in Japan that they intended to kill.
私はそのバスジャックは…
キラが日本に入った FBI の殺害を目的として…
FBI の情報を…
彼から盗む為に行われたとしか考えられないんです
そして、そのバスジャック犯の死は…事故によるもの
And the culprit ended up dead in an accident.
Basically, heart attacks are not the only way that Kira can kill!
つまり、キラの殺しの方法は、心臓麻痺だけではない…
バスジャック犯の死に方が、心臓麻痺でない
The bus hi-jack culprit didn't die of a heart attack. Therefore, Kira must be able to kill via methods other than heart attacks?
だから、キラが心臓麻痺以外でも殺せると…
Yes.
はい
I think your story requires a few leaps in logic...
少し話が、飛躍し過ぎてるにように思えますが…
No, the only explanation is that the culprit was being manipulated by Kira.
いいえ、バスジャック犯だけは
キラに操られていたとしか考えられないんです
何故です
Why's that?
Ever since he told me about the bus hi-jacking, something has been on my mind.
彼から、バスジャックの話を聞いた時からずっと気になっていて
Finally, I asked him about it when he was in a good mood.
…機嫌のいい時にそれとなく聞いたんです
Although he didn't give me a name, he very clearly said...
彼は相手の名前こそ言いませんでしたが…はっきり言いました
What?
何を？
That he had no choice but to show someone on the bus his FBI ID.
「やむを得ず、バスの中で FBI の ID を見せた」と…
The investigation was kept secret from the Japanese police, so there were orders that they were to never show their ID.
日本警察には極秘の捜査でしたから…
ID は一切出さないことになっていました
So, the fact that FBI agents were in Japan must have come from that.
だから…
日本に入った FBI の存在は、彼から漏れたとしか思えない
Wow! She's right.
すげぇ…当ってる
So this is the "hole" that Light has been worrying about.
ライトが心配してた穴ってこれの事か…
I see. A truth that only you could know, and vengeance for the fiancé that was taken from you, have led you to this answer...
なるほど…
貴方しか知らない事実と、
フィアンセを奪れた執念から、たどり着いた答えなわけですね
That Kira can kill people through other methods than just a heart attack.
キラが心臓麻痺以外でも人を殺せると…
Yes.
…はい
You have incredible powers of deduction, yet you are blinded by personal feelings.
素晴らしい推理力たが…私情は絡み、
強引になってしまっている勘は否めない
It feels like this is very much aggressive intuition.
However, there are ample reasons to justify investigating this theory.
しかし、この考えで捜査する価値は…十分あります
Your testimony will be very important.
重大な証言でもありますしね
Yes.
はい…！
If you're right, it'll be like you said.
もし正しければ、あなたの言った通り、
Kira will soon be caught.
キラはもうすぐ捕まるでしょう
何故なら、
After all, the person who your fiancé showed his ID to in the bus... is Kira.
あなたのフィアンセがバスの中で ID を見せた相手が…
キラなんですから…
Yes.
ええ…
That was close.
危ないところだったな…
If this woman had got to the police before I got to her...
この女が…僕より先に警察に話していたら…
しかし、どうやら死神じゃないほうの神は…
But it seems that gods other than the Shinigami... are on my side.
僕の味方らしい…
To be continued
この女がどんな死に方をするのか見てみたいが…
追いかけていく訳にもいくまい…
さぁ…死に急げ！